Himanshu Rajput

Gurugram ,Haryana | In: +918770836147 |

rajput25.himanshu@gmail.com | https://github.com/Himanshu25rajput

SUMMARY

Business strategist with a sound understanding of organizational development and lead generation. Skilled communicator with software development skills with good experience providing company with successful solutions to building organizational success. Innovative thinker who detects more efficient ways of growing company assets by recommending new idea, revolutionizing current product offerings and testing new market approaches.

EDUCATION

SIMPKINS PBLIC SCHOOL Gwalior, M.P. March 2013 Matriculation M.P BOARD SIMPKINS PUBLIC SCHOOL Gwalior, M.P. Higher Secondary Education M.P BOARD; PCM+B March 2015 JAIN GROUP OF COLLEGE Gwalior, M.P. Bachelor of computer application; Major in Computer Application June 2019 • Student Council member at Jain Jain group of College **ITM UNIVERSITY** Gwalior, M.P. Master of Computer Application; Major in Computer Application June 2022

• Cumulative GPA: 8.44/10

• Class President, Men's Cricket Club member

EXPERIENCE

KARVY CORPORATE COMPANY

DTH Complaint Handling August 2018 – January 2019

DIGITAL OCEAN

Android Developer

January 2022 -- April 2022

INSPIRIT VISION

IAM Analyst cyber security
July 2022 -- September 2022

BHAVYANSH INFOTECH

Business Development Executive

September 2022 - July 2023

EDUTECH SKILL

Technical Support July 2023 – April 2024

ADDITIONAL

Technical Skills: Lead generation, LinkedIn, Email referral, strategic planning, Advanced in MS office, Core java, XML, Rest API's, Proficient in MS word, MS Excel, MVVM architecture, LDAP, REST API, Spring Boot, Tomcat, Postman, Linux, Java, Spring Boot, Android Development, HTML, CSS. JavaScript.

Languages: Fluent in English.

Certifications: Completed CCA at the age of 10 (2008).

Awards: Won Umang competition out of 100+ participants (2017).